66.
It's.
Since.
So.
This is.
66.
In a simple button, actually.
Like what I have done is I have created a a library button.
So in Android studio, you have an option to create a library.
So I have created a library like that and I just put it over here.
Okay.
So I don't want to cover all those library creation part.
You can just Google it out.
How to create a library in Android studio.
And it's pretty straightforward because that will make the make the presentation too huge.
So that's why I just thought of ignoring that.
So you can do it on your own.
Like just Google it out and find out how to create a Android library and you just create the library
and just copy the files like this here.
So what I have done is in the framework super library, I copied the package and the Java file and the
resources here and also the Android manifest here.
So these are the three things I have copied over here.
Okay.
And then I have created the Android Dtmc.
So in the Android case, the same stuff.
So in this case it's a Java library.
So there are some small differences, like the local module, you give this one and then include build
Java library.
You need to include this as well.
Okay.
So what you can do is just copy this and the rest of the things almost all are similar because here
you can see so, so the local path is there.
And then all this is similar to our normal APK.
So the source files is taking all the Java files from this path.
Okay.
And then the local module optional.
And the local module in this case is com dot duper dot super library.
I think we have given the app name in the past here because that time we we build it from the app.
Okay.
So in this case we are building it from the source.
So that's why I have kept the Java file over here and I have to specify the package name here.
Okay.
And okay, so that's it here for the Android Dtmc.
And the manifest is a normal manifest library.
And then.
Okay.
And then there is one XML which you need to create and you will have to give the jar file name over
here like this.
And this is just giving a permission.
This is just setting a permission to access this jar file.
Okay.
So then, so this is just the Readme which was already existing.
So yeah.
Framework and overlay.
I have not done anything.
And the products.
What you need to do is you need to so so when you create a library, you can export, you have an option
to expose the packages which you want to the end user and you can make some other packages as hidden.
So if you add plus this one, you are giving the access to the end user.
So the add on steps definition.
So here you have to provide that.
Okay?
And here you have the Android dot products, Android products.mk So here you pass the super library.
MK Which is actually, um, which is a super library dot.
MK Uh.
Um, okay, so the super libraries in case here itself.
Okay.
So, so under the products um, Android products.mk, we give the super library product makefiles which
is actually super library dot, which is over here.
And in the super library, we define all the library related information.
Okay, so here you give the addon name, which is super library and the copy product copy files.
So basically you are telling to copy this file, which is actually com dot duper dot super library dot
XML from here to the system path.
So in your system image it will be copied after the build.
Okay.
And then the list of packages are given here.
So in this case I have only super library.
I don't have the super library client, so I'll just delete this.
Okay.
So I have just this one.
Um, yeah.
And then I have the copy file and then the super library.
And then.
Okay, then there is the manifest dot I and I and hardware dot Ini, which is actually inside.
So you can see device is one.
Okay.
So this also needs to be copied.
So here you have hardware.
This is quite empty and in the manifest you have the name of the super library vendor vendor in this
case is Duper.
And so if you are this is actually the OEM or the OEM name.
So if you are working for Samsung, then you just give Samsung here.
Okay.
And the description is the super library description.
And this is what is coming in the Android studio.
When you add the SDK header and here you give the version, I give 29 in this case and the revision
is one and the library is this one and this is the jar file and this is the skin.
Okay?
And this is what the default skin I have just used.
I didn't do anything.
There.
So it's the default skin name.
It's optional, actually.
Okay.
In this case, there is no skin name because I'm not using any skins.
In this case, it's just a pure button.
Okay.
And the hardware, this is blank.
And the source code property is just a blank file for now.
And the skin is something which is already existing there.
So I haven't used that for this example.
And we have the Android, which is the default one, which actually calls all the sub directory make
files and there is a clean spec which actually does the cleanup tasks later on and the rest of the files
are the same stuff.
Okay, this is an empty file again.
Okay.
So in order to build that, you need to do this.
Make j 8 or 16 depending on your core and the product hyphen widget add on hyphen SDK, underscore add
on.
So run run this in a short while.
So to summarize.
So it's not complicated.
I think I might have I might have explained it in a bad way, but it's quite simple.
So what I have done is I copied the sample.
And apps.
I'm not adding anything.
So if you want to add an app APK, just go ahead and add it.
So, and I just kept it as it is in the frameworks.
I added the add on, which is actually the library super library.
And so this is basically just a library which I created in Android studio.
So you can Google it out how to create.
Maybe I can show that quickly just for make it complete.
So if you go here, this is our mobile launcher.
Okay, so if I go here, you can create new and inside the new you can create a new module and here
you can select the Android library.
Or even you can select a Java code library.
So in this if I just create Java code library and I can just finish and it creates a new module here,
which is actually the library and I have created a button in this case which is an Android library and
okay, so I go.
Okay.
I got some error in this case.
Yeah.
So here it has created now.
Okay, so this error is due to.
Well, I don't know if this one's.
Now, it was due to that comment.
Okay.
So okay, that's irrelevant for us.
So in this so I have created a library here.
So and this is the class.
So this is the way you can create a library as well for your header.
So just go ahead and create one and copy the files and put it over the frameworks here.
Okay.
So in case if you face any issues or any confusion, please feel free to contact me.
And then you have the overlays.
I haven't touched that in this case and the products inside the product, you have to add the add ons
tab where you give the expose libraries and the Android products and all those other stuffs.
Okay.
And then the SDK add on, you have to define the hardware which is empty and manifestazioni, which
is quite important.
You need to specify the API, the name vendor, all those stuffs over here.
Okay.
And then source this is blank and the skin is as it is and the android is as it is and the clean spec
is as it is.
Okay.
So.
So that's it.
So now let's go ahead and try running it.
Okay.
Okay, So let's now go ahead and make the make the Android.
Sorry, make the add on.
Okay, So let's see.
Uh, so this is the add on name, which is the super library.
So the product name is Super Library.
So I think I have told you earlier that this is how you build the add on.
So this product is static, this is just product and the widget add on.
This is exactly what you need to change.
Okay?
And add on is also static.
So basically you need to just replace this with the add on name.
Okay.
So I think in the in the earlier videos, I think I have said it incorrectly, telling that this has
to be the product folder name that was wrong.
So it has to be just product which is always static and only this has to be replaced.
Okay, So let's go ahead and build this actually.
So let's come to the stuff.
Okay?
Okay.
So this is what we are going to make.
So we have make and the Js16 product hyphen Super libraries, our item name and SDK add down.
Okay, So let's click on Enter.
Okay, So now so it's not regenerating because I already built it once previously.
So that's why it is.
It got completed in nine seconds.
So let me just for demonstration, let me just change something.
Maybe I can change something inside.
Here.
Or not there.
So maybe.
Or.
Okay, maybe.
Inside my body.
My.
Oh, okay.
So let's change something inside.
Uh huh.
Not the product name.
Um.
So.
Okay, let's change something in the library.
So I'll just first try to make the build fail.
Just change frameworks to just framework so that it fails.
So let's see.
Okay.
So it already failed.
Men's commence before.
Okay.
It's May 3rd.
Okay, let's rename this.
Product supplier here.
Before the first target.
Commands.
Commands before first target.
Okay, so let's make the build fail.
Okay.
So now it has started again.
So it was identified that it's modified and it's regenerating.
So it should fail now because the path is incorrect.
I'll post the video for some time.
Okay, so it's.
99 percentage.
Okay, so it failed because this path is incorrect.
This path is incorrect.
Okay, So now let me just change it.
This is just for demonstration.
I just want to show you a complete build.
Okay.
So we just replaced it back and start it again.
Okay, So now it is including this thing.
It's regenerating.
So it has identified that is modified and it's regenerating.
So let it run now.
Okay, so it's going fast.
It will finish in one minute.
Good.
Yeah.
So now it is done.
Okay, so we have successfully created the SDK add on.
Okay.
So.
So that's the process.
So now let's check where exactly it has created the SDK.
So let's come here.
So basically we need to check in this out host SDK and on out host.
So let, let's come here.
I don't know.
Go to
be out.
The target, right?
It's in the host.
So inside the host Linux, it's 86.
And here, here it is.
So here you go.
So you have both the libraries here.
Okay, So.
So this is the zip file so you can share this zip file with anyone and they can use it.
So if you go inside, it has all these images plus your SDK and.
Okay, so the SDK should be here.
This is the one.
What is it?
The library lips.
I think it's.
It's inside the lips.
Okay.
It's under this one lips folder.
So here you go.
So that's it.
So.
So you can actually distribute this either locally within a web server or if you want, you can actually
host it in the internet and give it to a wider, wider user base.
Okay.
So yeah, so that's it.
So this was all about SDK add on.
Okay.
I would I would like you to try one, try creating one SDK on on your own and let me know the results.
Thank you.